royalcaribbean.com 2019-11-22

# Privacy Policy | Royal Caribbean Cruises

Categories of personal data | When/how We get it  
---|---  
  
**Personal, contact, ID and payment details** \- Your full name and contact details (first name, middle name, last name, nickname, suffix, email address, phone number, postal address, country of residence, emergency contact details), age, date of birth, gender, passport details, photograph, video footage (including CCTV footage), job title, visa details, dietary requirements, nationality, marital status, country of birth, payment card details and any publicly available content on social media platforms.

| 

You provide some of these details to Us if you book a cruise, sign up to receive Our emails, join Our loyalty programs, use Our Digital Platforms or interact with Our social media accounts (including by entering competitions). You might also provide these details to Us if you contact one of Our call centers. Where you book with a travel partner, We may receive these details from the travel partner. If another person books a cruise or contacts Us on your behalf, We will receive these details from them. We may also receive video footage of you from the CCTV cameras onboard Our ships.  
  
**Sensitive personal data** \- We may collect details relating to your health or medical conditions, including details of any accessibility requirements, allergies or other health-related requests. We also may collect details of your meal preferences which may tell Us about allergies or other dietary requirements, or potentially indicate your religion or beliefs.

| 

You provide some of these details to Us if you tell Us about medical conditions when you book with Us, check in for your cruise, request guest access or other accessibility services, visit one of Our medical facilities during a cruise and/or sign up to a shore excursion, tour or entertainment onboard a cruise.  
You might also provide these details to Us if you contact one of Our call centers. Where you book with a travel partner, We may receive these details from the travel partner. If another person books a cruise or contacts Us on your behalf, We may receive these details from them.  
  
**Your photograph and your image** \- We may collect a facial photograph of you before your cruise or during your cruise.

| 

We use your image for safety and security purposes, as described in 6(2)(c) below. If We have your consent to do so, We use the photo you provide to identify you during the embarkation process, to make boarding quicker, and We may allow Our Business Partners to access this data to verify your identify (e.g. where you request that Our onboard photographers prepare and send to you photos of you and those people you are travelling with).  
  
**Loyalty account details** \- a unique ID for your loyalty account, points balance, account activity, life milestones (e.g., anniversary date), and loyalty tier.

| 

We create these details for you when you join one of Our loyalty programs and update them as you credit bookings and other activity to your loyalty account.  
  
**Booking records** \- Details of past and future bookings with Us (including booking ID, cruise type, date of cruise, ship, passengers on your booking, destination, duration, price paid, cabin information and the date of booking) and bookings with Our Suppliers (including flight dates, flight number, airport destination, airline and frequent flyer ID).

| 

We compile this personal data from Our records when you book with Us. We also receive this personal data from Our Suppliers if you book with them.  
  
**Details about your travel patterns and preferences** \- The destinations that you travel to with Us, the length and the type of your vacation with Us including whether you travel with household members (e.g., family vacations), your propensity to book certain types of vacations or destinations or to re-book with Us within a specific timeframe and the marketing segments that We add you to.

| 

We compile this information from your booking records and Our profiling and personalized marketing activities – see Profiling and personalized marketing below.  
  
**Your marketing and data processing preferences** \- Whether you want to receive marketing communications from Us and how you would like Us to contact you.

| 

We keep a record of your marketing preferences when you tell Us about these, including the options you select in your guest account.  
  
**Technical information related to use of Our Digital Platforms - D** etails about the browser, device and internet connection that you use when you browse Our Digital Platforms, technical information, including your IP address, MAC address, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform. For example, Our Digital Platforms can tell whether you are using a mobile phone or a desktop computer.

| 

Your device provides this information when you use Our Digital Platform whether or not you are signed into your account or have accepted cookies.  
  
**Cookies** \- Our Digital Platforms store small text files on your device that identify your browser. See Cookies and other tracking technologies below for more details.

| 

When you visit Our Digital Platforms and use Our services that means We need to identify you (e.g., where you book a cruise, sign into your account, where you want Us to identify you as a member of Our loyalty programs and where We need to remember your preferences). Cookies can also be set when you open Our emails.  
  
**Information about your interactions with Our websites** \- As well as the technical information above, We collect information about your visits to Our websites, including the full web addresses that you access, your path of clicks, through and from Our site (including date and time and whether you used a search engine), products you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page and any phone number used to call Our customer service number.

| 

When you browse Our websites.  
  
**Information about your interactions with Our emails** \- We use elements embedded in Our emails (e.g., images and clear images) that let Us know whether you have opened or read an email. If you follow links in Our emails, We may also set cookies on your system if you have enabled cookies. This information also tells Us about your propensity to engage with Our emails.

| 

When you open and interact with email that We have sent you (unless you have opted out). We compile information about how you interact with Our emails from Our profiling and personalized marketing activities – see Profiling and personalized marketing below.  
  
**Information about the purchases you make onboard**  
We collect information about your purchases along with the loyalty number and transaction information to enable you to purchase products and/or activities as well as to obtain loyalty benefits.

| 

If you make purchases with Us prior to or during your cruise, We collect these details at the point of payment including through Our Digital Platforms, call center or from your SeaPass (if the purchase is made onboard).  
  
**Details relating to your use of onboard casinos**  
We track details of your play and spend in onboard casinos (including offer codes, your customer ID, spend, loyalty rewards details and gaming habits). We sometimes use these details to identify guests that may be interested in casino gaming.

| 

If you choose to use casinos onboard during your cruise, We collect these details when you play, including when you use your SeaPass card when you play. If you apply for credit for use at Our onboard casino, We will receive credit related information from Our credit check service provider.  
  
**Information relating to third party promotions and offers**  
We work with Our Business Partners so that you are able to use promotions and offers. To enable you to use these offers and promotions, We verify your details against those provided by Our Business Partners (such as the voucher number and expiration date).

| 

We receive these details from Our Business Partners if you have opted to receive promotions from them.  
  
**Profiling and personalized marketing**  
**9.1** Profiling overview: We think it is important for Us to understand the types of vacations that Our consumers are interested in so that We can make Our marketing relevant and targeted. To do this, We use your personal data to build a profile for you that lets Us work out which of Our marketing segments is the best fit for you.

**9.2** The personal data We use: From the personal data that We hold about you, which includes the personal data We receive from Our Suppliers and Our Business Partners, Our model may consider your age, gender, household or travel composition, postcode, how you have interacted with Our websites and marketing emails and your booking history (including your destinations, the ships you have sailed on and your chosen accommodation). We do not always use all of these data categories if We do not have the information about you or it is not relevant for Our marketing activities.

**9.3** How We build your profile and what We learn from it:

  1. **Statistical analysis -** We use the data above as inputs for a proprietary statistical model, the output of which can tell Us about your previous or likely future booking behavior, for example:
    1. the value or likely value of the bookings you make with Us;
    2. whether you tend to re-book within 12 months of your last cruise and the destinations that you tend to book; and
    3. the extent to which you engage with Our marketing emails.
  2. **Marketing segments -** We try to match every consumer with one or more pre-defined segments that allow Us to broadly tailor Our marketing messages for the right audience. We define Our segments using anonymized demographic data based on broad characteristics and behaviors such as age, household income, or location. You will share a segment with other consumers, so this process is generally not highly individualized.

**9.4 Here's an example:** Let’s say you have just signed up on Our websites (giving Us your contact details) and you have never booked a cruise before. Over the next few days you search for cruises that are generally popular with families (giving Us website interaction data). We might use that data to add you to one of Our family segments so that you get relevant emails from Us.

**9.5 What this means for you:** Tailoring Our marketing campaigns to your profile or segment means you should receive more relevant communications from Us. That’s good for Us because We think you are more likely to book a vacation that matches your requirements. We hope that’s good for you, too, because it helps you to find the vacations that you are interested in. We might also send you special offers on your birthday.

**9.6 Targeted advertising on third party social media platforms and websites:** We may share your personal data – including your name, email address, address and date of birth – with third party social media platforms, including Facebook, and websites for the purposes of allowing those platforms to display targeted advertisements to you. You can ask Us not to share your personal data with platforms, but you will need to contact the platform with any requests in relation to how the platform uses your personal data because We do not control that.

**9.7 You can opt out:** You are in control of your personal data. You can update your marketing preferences or opt out of personalized marketing at any time using your Guest Account or, where you do not have a Guest Account, by either clicking a link in an email marketing communication, replying STOP to an SMS text message or by calling the sender of any marketing communication.

 **Multi-guest reservations and linking reservations**  
**13.1** If you make a multi-guest reservation, all of the guests who are part of the reservation will be able to access the personal data of the other guests on Our Digital Platforms. 

**13.2** Our Digital Platforms will allow your reservation – as well as your personal data therein - to be associated to another user's guest account provided you have furnished certain credentials or unique identifiers to them. We call this "linking”. If your reservation is linked by another user of Our Digital Platforms, We will allow the user who has linked your account to (1) complete online check-in for you and others in your reservation, (2) view your boarding pass, and the boarding pass of others in your reservation, (3) pay for an onboard or shore product or activity for you or others in your reservation, using their own onboard expense account or their own payment methods, and (4) view eDocs associated to your reservation. However, they will not be able to modify or cancel your reservation, view your folio or use a digital key to access your stateroom.
